Kareem Rizk

Phone: (202) 621-4174 | Email: kareem.magdy5@gmail.com | Arlington, VA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kareem-rizk/

I Portfolio: https://kareem1990.github.io/KR-React-Portofolio-Ch20/I

GitHub: https://github.com/Kareem1990

Executive summary:

A web developer and designer with a special passion for coding and IT. Seeking a job as a front-end or back-end developer with knowledge and practical skills in MERNG stack and database work. I have just graduated from George Washington University's bootcamp in full stack web development, and am excited to start entering the programming field after 9 years of being a journalist and translator.

Technical skills

- JavaScript (Vanilla JS, JQuery, React)
- MERN stack
- CSS (Materialize, Bootstrap, React Bootstrap)
- HTML (Semantic HTML)
- Python (libraries: Matplot, Seaborn)
- MySql database
- GraphQl
- Tableau
- Git and Github
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Access)

Projects:

Woof Woof, Pet shelter | https://github.com/Kareem1990/adopt-a-pet | https://lit-thicket-52493.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Woof Woof foundation is a local pet rescue and adoption agency.
- Role: Github repo manager, Database models, Graphql Typedf and Resolvers, EmailJS and Styling.
- Tools: MERN Stack, Bootstrap React and Graphgl.

Travel-Optimizer, Traveling assistant https://github.com/Kareem1990/travel-optimizer/

- Summary: An app allows travelers to quickly plug their destination into the search to pull points of interest from selected cities
- Role: HTML, CSS (Materialize), integrating classes in JS files and Media queries.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Open Tri Map, Materialize, Mapbox.

Memes Masters, Memes social media | https://github.com/Kareem1990/meme-masters | https://github.com/

- Summary: An app to send strictly memes to friends. Sign up or log in and start sharing the laughs.
- Role: Front end designer, creating database and models and seeding data,
- Tools: Express, Express Handlebars, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, ORM.

Experience:

George Washington University Bootcamp

November 2021 - May 2022

Full Stack developer certificate program

- Built and styled static web pages with semantic HTML and CSS.
- Used Git to start projects, track changes, and host code via remote servers.
- Deployed a website to GitHub pages.
- Improved website interactivity by using Javascript and its frameworks like React.
- Applied the accepted and standard basics of social coding—including source control, and issue tracking.

MBN - Alhurra channel website

April 2018 - June 2021

Multimedia producer

- Retrieved the website from the production server, updated and modified pages and indexes. Pushed the updated pages to the production server.
- Acted as admin support to the webpage to grant permissions for new producers.
- Implemented modifications requested by users.
- Translated articles from Persian and English into Arabic.
- Pitched compelling story ideas to the editorial management team.
- Ensured accuracy of facts, grammar and spelling prior to review for publication.
- Monitored news sources to keep informed of related regional and international news.

The National Interest

Jan 2019 – June 2019

Intern

- Wrote reports and <u>articles</u> covering the MENA region.
- Translated from Arabic and Persian into English.

Iran Disinformation (Bethesda, Maryland)

July 2019 – December 2019

Translator

- Retrieved data from several sources including SQL Server, Access Databases, Excel.
- Downloaded and manipulated/cleaned multiple Relational Databases from several websites to be integrated into my weekly reports for the MENA region.
- Visualized Databases using Tableau, Python's Matplot library and Seaborn.
- Did research from several web resources and downloaded dynamic data, to conduct research on human rights and democratic transition.
- Translated from Persian into English and Arabic.
- Fact checked the Iranian news sources.

• Validated and verified data published on the Iranian regime media against global trusted sources, like world bank.

Arabic Post (Istanbul, Turkey)

Jan 2018 – April 2018

Journalist

- Wrote stories on politics (including Iranian affairs), lifestyle, culture and history.
- Translated articles from Persian and English into Arabic.
- Covered Arabic affairs especially Egyptian interests.
- Monitored news sources to keep informed of related regional and international news.
- Ensured all articles, videos, interviews and other content are well organized, timely, balanced.

Elwatan News (Giza, Egypt)

January 2015- August 2015

Journalist

- Covered the Iranian nuclear deal in 2015 by translating news from Persian media.
- Covered world news, particularly focusing on the Middle East.
- Served as an editor.
- Translated news articles from English and Persian into Arabic.

Education:

GW University Web Development bootcamp

November 2021 - May 2022

Certificate in full stack web development

Faculty of Dar-Alulum, Cairo University

September 2010 - June 2013

Bachelor of Arts in Arabic Language and Islamic Studies

Languages: Arabic, English, Persian